osqa.net 2018-11-24

# DZoneSoftware.com Privacy Policy

DZone, Inc. (“DZone”), the provider of the AnswerHub service, takes privacy very seriously. This Privacy Policy applies to the AnswerHub service and the web site at www.dzonesoftware.com, other sites using the “Powered by AnswerHub” engine, and related software (collectively, the “Service”). We are providing this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal information that we collect and receive from you in connection with the Service.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to: (1) activities that occur offline; or (2) to information we collect outside of the Service, including through [www.dzone.com](http://www.dzone.com/) and other websites not related to the AnswerHub Service provided by DZone.

This Service may be provided to you or recommended by our customer, which may be your employer or another third party (“Customer”). This Privacy Policy does not modify any agreements or privacy policies in place between you and any Customer. We encourage you to review any such documents and see how your personal information may be used or disclosed by any Customer.

**Privacy Shield**

DZone participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. DZone is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, you may visit [www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome). In particular, you may view participants in the Privacy Shield list at [www.privacyshield.gov/list](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, DZone is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (“FTC”).

You may direct any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of personal information to the DZone contact information below. DZone will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with the principles contained in this Policy. DZone has committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to the International Centre for Dispute Resolution/American Arbitration Association, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. For any Privacy Shield complaints that cannot be resolved with DZone directly, please contact or visit the ICDR/AAA at [www.icdr.org](https://www.icdr.org/icdr/faces/home;jsessionid=zEx1Len3-j6Kvp0t8dG5C1a5BnBWx-0CLvRBqqVY1m09AdKN-b-x!-2099758379?_afrLoop=35001107939733&_afrWindowMode=0&_afrWindowId=null#%40%3F_afrWindowId%3Dnull%26_afrLoop%3D35001107939733%26_afrWindowMode%3D0%26_adf.ctrl-state%3Ddop0a5qof_4) for more information or to file a complaint. The services of the ICDR/AAA are provided at no cost to you.

In addition, under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Personal Data Collected**

When inquiring about use of or using the Service, you may be required to provide certain personally identifiable information necessary for use of the Service and for communicating with you. The data collected includes information about you that can be used to contact or identify you, and information related to your use or potential use of Service (collectively, “Personal Information”). Personal Information that we collect may include without limitation name, email address, and phone number.

The main reason we collect Personal Information from you is to provide you an efficient and personalized user experience. The collection of Personal Information also enables our users to establish a user account that can be used to interact with other users through the Service. We use your Personal Information to provide the Service and respond to your Service-related inquiries.

Within our Service, if you interact with other users, the Service may share additional information with such other users. The additional information you share by participating in these types of communications is your choice and responsibility and the privacy of such information cannot be guaranteed. Similarly, information you share through messaging within our Service is solely your responsibility.

**Use of Cookies and Tracking Technologies**

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies as part of the Service. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any Personal Information you submit while using the Service.

We use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our Service. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. If you reject cookies, you may still use our Service, but your ability to use some areas of our Service will be limited.

On our general, marketing site, we also may use web beacons and other similar technologies to track your use of the site. We also may include web beacons in advertisements or email messages to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. The information we obtain in this manner enables us to customize our site and to measure the overall effectiveness of our site’s content, programming and other activities.

**Use and Disclosure of Information**

We do not sell, rent, use or share your personal information with others except as indicated in this Privacy Policy.

We may use your Personal Information to provide the Service, support and maintain the Service, improve and update the Service, communicate information to you that you have requested, for our marketing, research and development purposes, and for other purposes specified in this Privacy Policy or at the time information is requested from you.

Comments or questions sent to us using email or other messaging tools will be shared with our staff that is most likely to be able to address your concerns. We may archive your messages once we have provided you with a response. If we find your personal question valuable to community discussion, we reserve the right to post your question on the Service, after using reasonable efforts to remove any names or personal identification. Please note that email communications will not necessarily be secure; accordingly, you should not include sensitive information in email correspondence with us.

DZone may aggregate your information with other users’ information to determine and distribute aggregated statistics and information about the Service and its use and users. This aggregated information will not identify any specific user.

**DZone may also disclose Personal Information:**

  * when we have your permission to do so; or
  * to companies who work for DZone to provide one or more parts of the Service or that provide related administrative functions (such as support services and analytics). These third parties may have access to your personal information; if they do, this access is only so that they may perform these tasks on our behalf and they are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose; or
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to (1) comply with a legal process or law, or to respond to a subpoena, court order, or government request for information, (2) enforce Terms of Services and/or other agreements between you and DZone, (3) respond to claims that any content on the Service violates the rights of third parties, or that otherwise arise from your use of the Service, or (4) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of DZone, its users, or the public.
  * when required or permitted to do so by law for public safety. Disclosures may be made to protect you from a serious threat to your health or safety or to protect the health or safety of another person.

**Onward transfer of Information**

DZone will not disclose any personally identifiable information to a third party who is not a DZone contractor or agent (“Agent”) except as outlined above. For third parties acting as DZone’s Agent, DZone will ascertain that the third party subscribes to the Privacy Shield principles, is subject to the EU Data Protection Directive, or has entered into an agreement with DZone that is consistent with the Privacy Shield principles.

In the context of an onward transfer, DZone has responsibility for the processing of personal information it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to an Agent on its behalf. DZone shall remain liable under the Privacy Shield principles if its Agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with such principles, unless DZone proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

**Third Parties and Links**

This Privacy Policy applies only to our Service. We may provide links to other information and sites that we believe may be of interest to our users. Their sites may collect or request personally identifiable information from you. You should review the privacy policy of these sites before providing such information, as these sites are not covered by our Privacy Policy. We cannot guarantee the standards of sites to which we link or be responsible for the contents, or privacy practices and policies, of these and other third-party sites. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of every site you visit.

Our Service may include social media features, including the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the “share this” button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Service. These features may collect your IP address, where you are using our Service, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Service. Your interactions with these features and widgets are governed by the privacy policy of the company that created the feature.

**Access to Account**

If you are a registered user of the Service, you can change your account information through the user profile page under Settings in the Service. Also, upon request, DZone will grant you reasonable access to personal information that it holds about you. DZone will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, amend, or delete information that is shown to be inaccurate or incomplete. You may need to supply certain information so that we can try to verify that you have authority to modify this information.

In the event that Customer requests DZone to remove a user's Personal Information completely from the Customer’s community, DZone will remove such Personal Information within 30 days.

**Choice**

DZone will offer you the opportunity to choose (opt-out) whether their personal information is (a) to be disclosed to a third party (other than a DZone Agent), or (b) to be used for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you.

**Opt-Out**

You may opt-out of receiving certain marketing communications from us, by emailing us at info@dzonesoftware.com. In addition, all marketing e-mails from DZone will provide you with the opportunity to unsubscribe from future marketing mailings. Even if you opt out of such mailings, however, we reserve the right to send you e-mail and other communications to disclose maintenance and other service-related issues.

For sensitive personal information, DZone will give individuals the opportunity to affirmatively and explicitly (opt-in) consent to the disclosure of the information to a third party (other than a DZone Agent) or the use of the information for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individual.

DZone will provide you with reasonable mechanisms to exercise your choices.

**Legal Requirements**

We intend to protect your privacy to the fullest extent possible as described in this policy while also fulfilling our responsibility to uphold all applicable laws and regulations. Due to potential legal requirements and other possible circumstances, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed or accessed in ways not otherwise described in this policy. We may be compelled under law to disclose information to government or third parties under certain circumstances or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Further, we can, and you hereby authorize us to, disclose any information to law enforcement or other government officials that we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate in compliance with the law and/or government requests.

**United States**

Certain parts of the Service, including our general marketing site and our support systems, are hosted in the United States. If you are accessing the Service from outside the United States, please be advised that through your continued use of the Service, which is governed by U.S. law and this Privacy Policy, you are transferring your personal information to the United States and you consent to that transfer; subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

**Security Measures**

We have implemented reasonable and industry standard security measures on the Service to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the personal information under our control. We take reasonable measures to ensure that your information is reliable for its intended use, and is accurate, complete and current. Additionally, we take reasonable steps to ensure that our third party business partners, including our hosting partners, provide sufficient protection for personal information. We will take reasonable efforts to maintain Personal Information in the area (e.g., country or continent) as specified by our Customer. We will promptly make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored personal data.

You acknowledge that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, and that we cannot guarantee absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Service, you may contact us.

**Privacy of Children**

Children under age 13 are not permitted to use the Service. We will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information on the Service from children under 13. If we become aware that a user of the Service is under the age 13 and has provided us with Personal Information, we may delete such information from our files and may deactivate the related account.

**In the Event of Merger, Sale or Bankruptcy**

In the event that all or part of DZone is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, DZone may transfer or assign the personally identifiable information held by DZone as part of such merger, acquisition, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of DZone's bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, DZone may not be able to control how personal information is treated, transferred, or used.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

This policy may be revised by us from time to time. By using this Service you agree that we have a right to change our policy without prior notification. The revised policy will appear on our Service and/or web site with the date of last revision. Your continued use of the Service following such revisions will be conclusively deemed acceptance of any changes to these Terms.

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please email us or write to:

DZone, Inc.   
150 Preston Executive, Suite 201   
Cary, NC 27513 USA   
privacy@dzonesoftware.com

Last Revised: May 2018
